<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>READCHINA: lianhuanhua on Comics</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/</link><description>Recent content in READCHINA: lianhuanhua on Comics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://readchina.github.io/comics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About the translation</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/a-translation-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/a-translation-notes/</guid><description>This translation is the outcome of a joint translation project taught in the winter of 2020/2021 at the University of Freiburg. Our aim in this translation was to remain as faithful as possible to the Chinese original while at the same time conveying a tone of narration in line with a comic book addressed to young readers based on a &amp;ldquo;classical&amp;rdquo; piece of children&amp;rsquo;s literature. As the story takes place in early 20th century Russia, the given names of the characters are given in Russian.</description></item><item><title>About the translation</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/a-translation-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/a-translation-notes/</guid><description>In preparing this translation, our aim was to produce a text that would do justice to the legacy of Lu Xun, but more so, to the language and contents of the PRC adaptation of the story. In his essay accompanying his retranslation of the original short story into German, Hans Peter Hoffmann (2015) makes a convincing argument for the use of slightly outdated terms as markers for what Lu Xun wanted to emphasize as backward in his times.</description></item><item><title>Front and back cover</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-cover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-cover/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Front and back cover</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-cover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-cover/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Front and back cover</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-cover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-cover/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Frontmatter</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-front/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-front/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Frontmatter</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-front/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-front/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Frontmatter 01</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-front-i/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-front-i/</guid><description>Preface to the 1957 edition # (not shown above)
内容说明 # 祥林嫂年轻的时候死了丈夫，便到鲁四老爷家帮工。后来她婆婆又强迫她嫁人。不久她的第二个丈夫病死了，她的儿子被狼吃掉了，她被生活所逼，只好又回到鲁四老爷家里。鲁四老爷厌恶她死过两个丈夫，说她不干净，败坏风俗。她怪自己的命不好，听了柳妈的话，到土地庙里捐一条门槛，当撖替身赎罪，可是人家还一样鄙视她。她更加衰老了，精神更迟钝了，终于她被赶出了鲁家，变成乞丐死了。 Explanation of the contents # After Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife lost her husband early in life, she comes to the Lu household as a servant. Later on, her mother-in-law forces her to remarry. Soon after, her second husband dies of illness, and her son is eaten by a wolf. She has no choice but to return to the Lu household.</description></item><item><title>Frontmatter 02</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-front-ii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-front-ii/</guid><description>前言 # 《祝福》描写了一个淳朴的劳动妇女祥林嫂。丈夫死后,她为了逃避被出卖的命运，便来到鲁镇，在地主鲁四家里做工。但不久仍被婆家绑回去，逼嫁到山村里。&amp;ldquo;她一路只是嚎，骂&amp;rdquo;，后来还&amp;quot;一头撞在香案角上&amp;quot;，不惜以自己的生命来反抗旧社会、旧礼教的压迫。当她再一次在鲁四家里出现，那是第二个丈夫病死，儿子被狼叼走之后。因她再嫁再寡，鲁四把她看成不祥之物，暗暗告诫家人不许她沾手祭品。镇上的人由于受到封建礼教的毒害，也跟着嘲笑她。柳妈又以&amp;quot;阴间&amp;quot;的锯刑来恐吓她，要她到土地庙捐一条门槛，当作赎罪的替身，给千人踏，万人跨。她为了自己的生存，不断挣扎，捐了门槛；但仍然无效，主人还是不许她摆设祭品。她从此精神失常，象一个木偶人。不久被鲁四赶走，成为乞丐。最后怀着对&amp;quot;阴间&amp;quot;的恐怖和疑惑，在年终&amp;quot;祝福&amp;quot;时，死在街头上。 Preface # &amp;ldquo;The New Year&amp;rsquo;s Sacrifice&amp;rdquo; describes the simple female worker Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife. After the death of her husband, she comes to Luzhen to work in the household of Landlord Lu to escape the fate of being sold off. But before long, she is kidnapped by the family of her mother-in-law and forced to remarry into a mountain village. &amp;ldquo;She howled and cursed the whole way&amp;rdquo;, and later also &amp;ldquo;bumped her head against the corner of the incense burner table&amp;rdquo;, to resist to the oppression of old society and old Confucian ethics with her own life.</description></item><item><title>Frontmatter 03</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-front-iii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-front-iii/</guid><description>祥林嫂的一生是受压迫受欺辱的一生，是不断挣扎和反抗的一生，但以孔孟之道为反动理论基础的封建社会的四大绳索&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;政权、族权、神权和夫权却紧紧地束缚她。她不仅在物质上、肉体上受尽压榨和摧残，而且在精神上也受尽种种鄙视和嘲笑；不仅生前哀哀无告，还须怀着恐怖走向死亡&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;对于她，不是意味着悲惨生活的结束，而是成了另一种最大的恐怖的开始，这就深刻揭露了封建礼教和迷信勾结一起残酷压迫劳动人民的本质。祥林嫂的形象，是鲁迅深刻地概括了封建社会千百万被压迫人民的遭遇而写成的一个悲惨的典型人物，它有力地控诉了孔老二反动礼教的思想实质和封建主义制度的野蛮性和残酷性。杀人不见而血的刽子手鲁四，就是孔老二的徒子徒孙。鲁迅先生写这篇作品，就是为了号召人民向这些吃人的势力进行斗争。
在当前批林批孔的斗争中，《祝福》对于识破孔孟之道的反动本质有着一定的意义，困此我们编绘这本连环画出版。
The life of Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife was a life filled with oppression and humiliation, a life of constant struggle and resistance. But the four major feudal bonds &amp;ndash; political authority, kinship authority, theocratic authority and patriarchic authority &amp;ndash; bound her tightly to the Confucian and Menzian doctrines, which serve as the basis of the reactionary feudal society. She not only suffered severely from material and physical oppression and destruction, but also suffered psychologically from all sorts of contempt and mockery.</description></item><item><title>Page 01</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-01/</guid><description>彼帝加对做过的事情都糊涂得很。他在市场里到处走，什么都想过了。他又懊恼、又伤心。他饿得很，想买点儿吃的，可是口袋里一分钱也没有。 Petka was confused about the things he had done. He walked around the marketplace thinking about all sorts of things. He was frustrated and sad. He was terribly hungry and wanted to buy something to eat, but he did not have any money in his pocket.</description></item><item><title>Page 01</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-01/</guid><description>抗日战争时期，河北省乐亭县靠滦河的东岸，有一个张家庄，是抗日根据地的边沿区。这个庄的抗日组织在共产党的领导下，按照毛主席的军事路线，积极开展抗日斗争。 During the War of Resistance Against Japan, there was a place named Zhangjia Village, located on the east bank of the Luan River in Laoting County, which was in the border area of an anti-Japanese base. The village&amp;rsquo;s anti-Japanese organization was under the leadership of the Communist Party and actively carried out the anti-Japanese struggle in accordance with Chairman Mao&amp;rsquo;s military line.</description></item><item><title>Page 01</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-01/</guid><description>有一年初冬，鲁镇鲁四老爷家里要换女工，做中人的卫老婆子带来了一个女工，年纪大约二十六，七岁，脸色青黄，但两颊却还是红的。 One year in early winter, the family of Mr. Lu in the town of Luzhen wanted to change their female worker. Old Wei, who acted as a middlewoman, brought a female worker, roughly 26 or 27 years old. She had a sallow face, but her cheeks were still reddish.</description></item><item><title>Page 02</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-02/</guid><description>忽然，他看见一个女人在卖蛋饼，那蛋饼焦黄、松脆，还冒着热气。他馋得直流 口涎，于是走过去，拿起一个蛋饼，嗅了一嗅，塞在袋子里，转身走开了。 All of a sudden, he saw a woman selling pancakes which were brown, crisp and gave off hot steam. His mouth was watering, so he went and took one of the pancakes, smelled it, stuffed it in his pocket, turned around and walked away.</description></item><item><title>Page 02</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-02/</guid><description>一九四二年夏天，盘踞在河西据点里的日寇，特务，伪军，经常出来抓老百姓，抢东西。村里人都恨透了这帮坏蛋。有一天，敌人到河东&amp;quot;讨伐&amp;quot;。把抗属张大爷种的一亩西瓜凡熟的都给抢吃了，临走还把他打了一顿。 In the summer of 1942, Japanese invaders, spies, and puppet soldiers were stationed on the west side of the Luan River and often came out to take captive civilians and steal their things. Everyone in the village detested these bastards. One day, the enemy arrived at the east side of the river to &amp;ldquo;punish&amp;rdquo; the locals. They robbed and ate all the ripe watermelons on the patch of Uncle Zhang, a military dependent.</description></item><item><title>Page 02</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-02/</guid><description>卫老婆子叫她祥林嫂，说是自己母家的邻舍，死了当家人，所以出来做工。鲁四老爷皱了皱眉，鲁四太太已经知道了他的意思，是在讨厌她是一个寡妇。 Old Wei called her Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife, said she was her maternal family&amp;rsquo;s neighbour, and she came out to work because her husband had died. Mr. Lu frowned, and his wife immediately knew what he meant, that he disliked the status of Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife as a widow.</description></item><item><title>Page 03</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-03/</guid><description>那女人追了过来，一把抓住他的肩膀，嚷道:&amp;ldquo;你偷东西！还我蛋饼！&amp;rdquo; The woman chased after him, grabbed his shoulder and shouted: &amp;ldquo;You thief! Give back my pancake!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 03</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-03/</guid><description>张大爷连伤带气，一病就起不来炕。那块西瓜地也就没人收拾了。 Uncle Zhang was injured and annoyed, and he was bedridden. Also, no one was able to tidy up the watermelon patch.</description></item><item><title>Page 03</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-03/</guid><description>但鲁四太太看祥林嫂模样还周正，手脚都壮大，很像一个安分耐劳的人，便不管四老爷的皱眉，将她留下试工了。 But Mrs. Lu thought her appearance very presentable, with strong hands and feet, and she looked like an honest and hard-working person, so she and kept her for a trial period regardless of Mr. Lu&amp;rsquo;s frown.</description></item><item><title>Page 04</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-04/</guid><description>随着那女人的叫嚷声，一下子围上一大群人。人们把他拖在地上，毒打了一顿，接着又把他拉到警察局去。 Following the woman&amp;rsquo;s shouting, a group of people immediately gathered around them. They dragged him to the floor, beat him relentlessly and took him to the police station.</description></item><item><title>Page 04</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-04/</guid><description>村干部研究了一下，决定委托儿童团看管瓜田。儿童团把这个任务交给了一个最勇敢而又有斗争经验的团员&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;泥鳅。 Therefore, the village cadres discussed the matter and decided to entrust the Children&amp;rsquo;s Corps to take care of the melon patch. The Children&amp;rsquo;s Corps then gave this task to one of the bravest and most experienced League members: Niqiu.</description></item><item><title>Page 04</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-04/</guid><description>试工期内，祥林嫂 整天的做，似乎闲着就无聊，她又有力，简直抵得过一个男子，所以第三天就定局，每月钱五百文。 During the trial period, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife worked around the clock and seemed to get bored whenever she was idle. Besides, she was so strong that she could compete over a man, so on the third day, it was settled that she would stay and earn 500 wen per month.</description></item><item><title>Page 05</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-05/</guid><description>他被拘留了。他仰望窗外清朗、明净和蓝的发亮的天空，苦恼在脑子里打转：人生是多么糟糕！只为了一个蛋饼&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; 他只等待着临头的命运。 He was held in custody and looked outside the window at the bright, clear and shining sky as his sorrows were whirling around his head: &amp;ldquo;Life is so terrible! Only for a pancake…&amp;rdquo; He was just waiting for his impending fate.</description></item><item><title>Page 05</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-05/</guid><description>瓜地和村子隔着半里路宽的一个大水坑,坑里长着芦苇。泥鳅是穷人家的孩子，从小就学会了干活。他的水量很大，自从接受了看瓜的任务后，他每天都游水过去，照料西瓜。 The watermelon patch and the village were separated by a big water pond, half a mile wide with reeds growing inside. Niqiu came from a poor family and had learned to work hard since he was a small kid. He was a good swimmer, so after he had accepted responsibility to protect the melons, he swam over each day to tend to the watermelons.</description></item><item><title>Page 05</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-05/</guid><description>祥林嫂不很爱说话，别人问了才回答，答的也不多。直到十几天之后，别人陆续的知道：她家里还有严厉的婆婆，一个小叔子；她是春天没了丈夫的，她丈夫活着时打柴为生，比她小十岁。大家所知道的也就只是这一点。 Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife did not talk much and answered only when addressed, and her answers were brief. A dozen days had passed before other people learned bit-by-bit, that she had a harsh mother-in-law at home and a younger brother-in-law; she had lost her husband in the spring; her husband, 10 years younger than her, had gathered firewood for a living before he died. These were all that people knew about her.</description></item><item><title>Page 06</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-06/</guid><description>忽然，传来一阵敲击木头隔板的声音:&amp;ldquo;老爷！同志！放我出去吧！看在老天爷面上！我的孩子们在等我呢!&amp;ldquo;一股浓烈的酒气涌了过来。原来那是个醉汉。 Suddenly, he noticed a tapping sound on the wooden wall: &amp;ldquo;Masters! Comrades! Let me out! In the name of God! My children are waiting for me!&amp;rdquo; A wave of boozy breath came over. It turned out to be a drunkard.</description></item><item><title>Page 06</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-06/</guid><description>泥鳅到了地理，总是闲不住，不是打瓜蔓，就是剜地蚕，嘴里还喊着：&amp;ldquo;沙瓤的大西瓜，谁吃谁甜掉牙！&amp;rdquo; At the patch, Niqiu always was busy. When he was not cutting the melon vines, he was picking out earthworms, all the while shouting: &amp;ldquo;A huge watermelon full of mushy pulp sweetens everyone&amp;rsquo;s life!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 06</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-06/</guid><description>日子很快的过去了，她的做工却毫没有松懈。人们都说鲁四老爷家里雇着了女工，实在比勤快的男人还勤快。到年底，扫尘，洗地， 杀鸡，宰鹅，彻夜的煮福礼， 全是一人担当，竟没有添短工。她的口角边渐渐的有了笑影，脸上也白胖了。 The days passed quickly, but her work never slacked off. Everyone said the female worker employed by Mr. Lu indeed was more diligent than a diligent man. By the end of the year, sweeping the dust, washing the ground, killing the chickens, slaughtering the geese, and preparing blessing ceremonies all night long, all of which were done by her alone without additional short-term helpers. The corners of her mouth gradually had a hint of a smile, her face also grew fairer and plumber.</description></item><item><title>Page 07</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-07/</guid><description>真是可笑极了。&amp;ldquo;傻瓜，&amp;ldquo;彼帝加说，&amp;ldquo;我怎么能放你出去呢？我也是像你一样，关在这里的呀！&amp;rdquo; This was ridiculous! &amp;ldquo;You fool&amp;rdquo;, Petka said, &amp;ldquo;how can I let you out? I am locked up in here just like you!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 07</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-07/</guid><description>由于泥鳅热心的收拾，又赶上雨水勤，瓜蔓爬满了地，小瓜又顶上来了，不到半月时间，个个长得比量米的柳条斗子还大。 Because of Niqiu&amp;rsquo;s enthusiastic work, and the frequent rainfalls, the melon vines crawled over the whole field and the small watermelons began to grow again. Before half a month had passed, they had all grown even bigger than Niqiu&amp;rsquo;s wicker basket.</description></item><item><title>Page 07</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-07/</guid><description>新年才过，祥林嫂从河边淘米回来时，忽而失了色，说刚才远远的看见一个男人在对岸徘徊，很像夫家的堂伯，恐怕是正为寻她而来了。鲁四太太很惊疑，打听底细，她又不说。 Just after the new year, once when Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife came back from rinsing rice by the river, she suddenly went pale and said that she just saw from afar a man pacing up and down on the other side of the riverband, who looked very similar to her husband&amp;rsquo;s cousin. She was afraid that he had come to find her. Mrs. Lu was suspicious, but when she asked for details, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife would not say anything.</description></item><item><title>Page 08</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-08/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;局长同志，请您放我出去吧！你瞧，这是多好的一块金表呀！&amp;ldquo;果然，从板缝里伸过一只手，手掌里托着一块闪闪发光的金表。表链上还挂着各式各样的小玩艺。 &amp;ldquo;Comrade director, please let me free! Look at this wonderful golden watch!&amp;rdquo; Sure enough, there was a hand reaching through the gap in the wall. There was a twisting sparkling golden watch in its palm. All sorts of little charms were hanging on the watch chain.</description></item><item><title>Page 08</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-08/</guid><description>村里帮着泥鳅把熟了的西瓜及时摘下来，拉到集上卖掉，用卖瓜的钱给张大爷买药、治病。 The village people helped Niqiu pick the ripe watermelons in time and brought them to the market to sell them. With the money they earned, they bought medicine for Uncle Zhang and cured his injuries.</description></item><item><title>Page 08</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-08/</guid><description>鲁四老爷一知道，就皱一皱眉，对四太太说：这不好。恐怕她是逃出来的！
When Mr. Lu found out about this, he frowned and said to his wife: &amp;ldquo;This isn&amp;rsquo;t good. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid she ran away from her family!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 09</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-09/</guid><description>彼帝加清晰地听到那表滴答地响，他的心也跟着猛跳起来。&amp;ldquo;嘿，真走运！&amp;ldquo;他抓过表，快活得喘不过气，血忽地涌到小脑瓜里去了。 Petka could clearly hear the watch ticking, and his heart started to beat in time with the watch. &amp;ldquo;How lucky!&amp;rdquo; He grabbed the watch so happy he could hardly breathe, and suddenly the blood rushed to his head.</description></item><item><title>Page 09</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-09/</guid><description>一天，泥鳅把一个熟透了的大西瓜摘下来，洑着水把瓜运到张大爷家里。 One day, Niqiu picked a very ripe watermelon. He took it to Uncle Zhang&amp;rsquo;s home by letting it float down the water.</description></item><item><title>Page 09</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-09/</guid><description>此后大约十几天，卫老婆子忽而带了一个女人来了，说是祥林嫂的婆婆。那女人虽是山里人模样，然而应酬很从容，说她特地来叫她的儿媳回家去，因为开春事务忙，家中人手不够。 About ten days later, Old Wei suddenly brought a woman, saying that she was the mother-in-law of Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife. Although the woman looked like a peasant from the mountains, her social manner was very decent. She explained that she was here to take her daughter-in-law back home as her family was short of labor in the start of a busy spring.</description></item><item><title>Page 10</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-10/</guid><description>那醉汉顿着脚，好像给枪剌着一样大叫着：&amp;ldquo;救命呀！强盗&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;彼帝加吓坏了，紧紧抓着那块表。忽然，他想出了一个好主意。 The drunkard stomped his feet and yelled as if he had been stabbed: &amp;ldquo;Ah, help! Bandits&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Petka was scared and held the watch tightly. All of a sudden, he had a good idea.</description></item><item><title>Page 10</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-10/</guid><description>这时，张大爷的病已好多了，他见泥鳅送了瓜来，便高兴得一骨碌坐起来。泥鳅抱着大西瓜，叫他尝尝。 By then, Uncle Zhang was feeling a lot better. When he saw Niqiu bringing the watermelon, he sat up, rejoicing. Niqiu held the huge watermelon in his arms and asked Uncle Zhang to try it.</description></item><item><title>Page 10</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-10/</guid><description>鲁四老爷说：&amp;ldquo;既是她的婆婆要她回去，那有什么话可以说呢。&amp;ldquo;于是算清了工钱，祥林嫂一文没有用，都交给婆婆。那女人又取了衣服，道过谢，出去了。其实已经是正午。 Mr. Lu said, &amp;ldquo;now that her mother-in-law wants her to go home, what can we say?&amp;rdquo; Then they settled her wages. As Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife had not used a single coin, the entire sum was handed over to her mother-in-law. The woman picked up the clothes of Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife, thanked Mr. Lu, and then left. It was already midday.</description></item><item><title>Page 11</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-11/</guid><description>他把表链和那些小玩艺一起揪下来，塞进板缝：&amp;ldquo;喏，拿去！&amp;ldquo;那醉汉已经糊涂了，早把表忘记了。他接过表链，喃喃地说：&amp;ldquo;多谢！多谢！我的心肝！&amp;rdquo; He pulled off the chain with the charms and stuffed it through the gap: &amp;ldquo;Here, take it!&amp;rdquo; The drunkard was muddle-headed. He had already forgotten about the watch. He took the chain and murmured: &amp;ldquo;Thanks a lot! Thanks a lot! My precious!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 11</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-11/</guid><description>张大爷接过瓜，把瓜贴在耳朵上，听了又拍，拍了又听，嘴里不住称赞：&amp;ldquo;好瓜！好瓜！这瓜给多少钱也不卖，留着做种。&amp;rdquo; After Uncle Zhang took the melon, he held it very close to his ear, listening and patting, patting and listening. He could not stop praising: &amp;ldquo;Such a good watermelon! Such a good watermelon! No matter how much money they give us, we&amp;rsquo;re not selling this one. We keep it for making seeds.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 11</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-11/</guid><description>好一会，四太太这才惊叫起来：&amp;ldquo;啊呀，米呢？祥林嫂不是去淘米的么？&amp;ldquo;于是大家分头寻淘箩。四太太先到厨下，再到堂前，后到卧房，全不见淘箩的影子。 After a while, Mrs. Lu cried out, &amp;ldquo;Ah, where is the rice? Didn&amp;rsquo;t Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife go out to rinse the rice?&amp;rdquo; People scattered up to look for the rice basket. Mrs. Lu checked the kitchen, then the hall, afterwards the bedroom, but she didn&amp;rsquo;t see even a shadow of it.</description></item><item><title>Page 12</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-12/</guid><description>太阳在窗外放光，表在彼帝加手里发亮。他想：聪明人说得对，因祸得福。这表值五十卢布&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;把它卖了，我得买个白面包，还有猪油、香肠、靴子、带条纹的汗衫&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; The sun was shining outside the window, and the watch was gleaming in Petka&amp;rsquo;s hand. He thought: &amp;ldquo;The wise man was right about gaining profit by misfortune. This watch is worth 50 Roubles… after selling it, I&amp;rsquo;ll buy myself white bread and lard, sausages, boots, and also a striped undershirt…&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 12</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-12/</guid><description>泥鳅拿起刀，在西瓜把儿上，&amp;ldquo;嗖&amp;rdquo; 地一旋，碗大的一块西瓜皮掉下来，露出鸡冠子色的沙瓤，瓤里包着油亮亮的黑籽。他们都用小勺挖着吃，把西瓜籽吐出来留作籽用。 Niqiu picked up a knife, and &amp;ndash; WHOOSH &amp;ndash; let it down on the watermelon. A large piece of the watermelon fell off and revealed the cockscomb-coloured melon pulp, which was covered with shiny black seeds. They both dug out some pulp with small spoons and ate it, spitting out the watermelon seeds in order to use them as seeds.</description></item><item><title>Page 12</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-12/</guid><description>四老爷踱出门外，也不见，直到河边，才见淘箩平平正正的放在岸上，旁边还有一株菜。 Mr. Lu checked outside, and did not find any trace of it either. He finally found it placed neatly on the river bank, with a bunch of vegetables next to it.</description></item><item><title>Page 13</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-13/</guid><description>一切都很好。只有一样不好，就是像罐子里的老鼠一样被关住了。&amp;ldquo;不要紧！&amp;ldquo;他安慰自己，&amp;ldquo;晚上，市场一收摊子，他们就放我了。&amp;ldquo;可是时间又是多么长呀！太阳简直一点儿也不着急。 Everything was fine. Only one thing was not fine, to be locked up like a mouse in a jar. &amp;ldquo;Never mind!&amp;rdquo; He comforted himself, &amp;ldquo;in the evening, once the market closes, they will let me go.&amp;rdquo; But how slowly the time passed! The sun was not in a hurry at all.</description></item><item><title>Page 13</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-13/</guid><description>吃完瓜，泥鳅抱着掏空了的大西瓜皮，在西瓜皮上挖了两个小洞，把西瓜皮往头上一套，象个大头娃娃似的，扭搭起秧歌，到坑沿上去了。 After eating the melon, Niqiu held the hollowed-out watermelon skin, cut two small holes into it and put the watermelon peel on his head, so he looked like a big-headed doll. Dancing a Yangge, he went to the edge of the water pond.</description></item><item><title>Page 13</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-13/</guid><description>看见的人报告说，河里面上午就停了一只白篷船，篷是全盖起来的。待到祥林嫂出来淘米，刚刚要跪下去，船里便突然跳出两个男人来，像是山里人，一个抱住她，一个帮着，拖进船去。 Bystanders reported that there had been a boat moored on the river since the morning, fully covered with a white canopy. When Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife knelt down to wash the rice, two men looking like peasants from the mountains suddenly jumped out of the boat. One man caught her and, with the help of the other, dragged her into the boat.</description></item><item><title>Page 14</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-14/</guid><description>他又仔细看了看那表，才把它塞在破烂的裤袋里。为了牢靠，他把袋子打了一个结。不一会儿，们锁响了，一个警察走进来叫他出去。彼帝加高兴地跳了起来，提一提裤子，跟着警察走出禁闭室。 Carefully, he looked at the watch and put it into the pocket of his tattered trousers. Just in case, he tied the pocket with a knot. After a while, the door opened, a policeman walked in and called him out. Rejoicing, Petka jumped up, pulled up his pants and followed the policeman out of the guardroom.</description></item><item><title>Page 14</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-14/</guid><description>泥鳅来到了水坑边上，水坑里有很多洗澡玩的孩子，扑通扑通地打着水。泥鳅悄悄地往水里一钻，只有一个套在头上的大西瓜皮留在水面上。 When Niqiu came to the edge of the water pond, a lot of children were washing and playing in the water, splashing the water. Niqiu quietly waded into the water, only the watermelon peel was visible on the surface.</description></item><item><title>Page 14</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-14/</guid><description>又说，祥林嫂还哭喊了几声，此后便再也没有什么声息，大约给用什么堵住了罢。接着就走上两个女人来，一个不认识，一个就是卫老婆子。窥探舱里，不很分明，祥林嫂像是捆了躺在船板上。 They continued to report, that Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife cried out a few times and then fell into silence. Her mouth was probably stuffed by something. Afterwards, two women appeared, one of them unknown, the other one Old Wei. The bystanders peeped in. It was not quite clear, but Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife seemed to be tied up lying on the deck.</description></item><item><title>Page 15</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-15/</guid><description>彼帝加被带进局长办公室。&amp;ldquo;你好！小扒手。&amp;ldquo;局长问，&amp;ldquo;你什么时候生的？&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;不知道，可是我十一岁了。&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;好像是第七次到我这儿来做客吧？我的判决是原谅你年幼无知，送你到少年教养院去。&amp;ldquo;彼帝加的头嗡的一声胀大了。 Petka was taken into the chief's office. &amp;ldquo;Hello, little pickpocket! When were you born?&amp;rdquo; The chief asked. &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know, but I am eleven years old.&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;You seem to be my guest for the seventh time? My decision is to forgive you your youth and ignorance, and send you to the reformatory.&amp;rdquo; Petka&amp;rsquo;s head started to buzz.</description></item><item><title>Page 15</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-15/</guid><description>一个孩子眼尖，站在水里喊道：&amp;ldquo;看那有个大西瓜，大西瓜！&amp;ldquo;一个猛子游过去，要去打捞大西瓜。 One of the children had sharp eyes. He stood in the water and shouted: &amp;ldquo;Look, there&amp;rsquo;s a huge watermelon, a huge watermelon!&amp;rdquo;, a courageous child swam over to get the huge watermelon out of the water.</description></item><item><title>Page 15</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-15/</guid><description>午饭之后，卫老婆子又来了。四老爷说：&amp;ldquo;可恶！&amp;ldquo;四太太愤愤地说：&amp;ldquo;你自己荐她来，又合伙劫她去，成个什么样子？你拿我们家里开玩笑么？&amp;rdquo; Old Wei came again after lunch. Mr. Lu said, &amp;ldquo;How dreadful is this!&amp;rdquo; Mrs. Lu said angrily, &amp;ldquo;It was you yourself who recommended her to work here, and now you just helped others to kidnap her back, what is this? Are you trying to make a joke out of our family?&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 16</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-16/</guid><description>更糟糕的是，局长命令警察搜他的身。他想：从此永远分手了，我的宝贝表！幸亏警察嫌脏，不肯动手。 To make matters worse, the chief ordered the policeman to search his body. He thought: &amp;ldquo;Farewell forever, my beloved watch.&amp;rdquo; Fortunately, the policeman disliked filth and was unwilling to move.</description></item><item><title>Page 16</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-16/</guid><description>其他的孩子也看到了，停止了&amp;quot;捉水猫猫&amp;quot;的游戏，都去捞那个大西瓜。西瓜在水面上一浮一浮的，孩子们追的快，瓜也游的快。 Other children also saw it, so they stopped the game of &amp;ldquo;catch the water cat&amp;rdquo; and went to catch the huge watermelon. The watermelon was floating on the surface. As the children were chasing it fast, it was also swimming fast.</description></item><item><title>Page 16</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-16/</guid><description>卫老婆子连忙说：&amp;ldquo;啊呀啊呀! 我真上当。对不起，四老爷，四太太。她来求我荐地方，我哪里料得到是瞒着她的婆婆的呢。这一回我一定荐一个好的来折罪&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;。&amp;rdquo; Old Wei answered hurriedly, &amp;ldquo;Ah, ah! I was fooled. I apologize for this, Mr. and Mrs. Lu. She had come to me and begged for a work recommendation. How could I have known that she concealed this from her mother-in-law? Next time, I will find someone better to make up for the mistake.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 17</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-17/</guid><description>局长对警察说：&amp;ldquo;不搜也罢，这不关紧要。你带上公文，把这小浪子交给少年教养院去。&amp;ldquo;警察把公文塞在皮包里，对彼帝加说：&amp;ldquo;流浪儿，走吧！&amp;ldquo;彼帝加庆幸地一提裤子，迈开大步便走。 The chief said to the policeman: &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t search, it doesn't matter. Take this document and bring this little hooligan to the reformatory.&amp;rdquo; The policeman stuffed the document into his briefcase and turned to Petka: &amp;ldquo;Hooligan, let's go!&amp;rdquo; Happily, Petka pulled up his pants and followed with big steps.</description></item><item><title>Page 17</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-17/</guid><description>一个机灵的孩子停住了，喊道:&amp;ldquo;别追了，这西瓜有 '鬼'，这是引咱们往深水里去，好淹死我们。&amp;ldquo;孩子们都害怕了，不敢再追。 A clever child stopped and yelled: &amp;ldquo;Stop chasing, there&amp;rsquo;s a ghost in this watermelon, it&amp;rsquo;s leading us into the deep water to drown us.&amp;rdquo; The children got scared and did not dare to continue their chase.</description></item><item><title>Page 17</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-17/</guid><description>原来祥林嫂瞒着她婆婆出来做工, 她婆婆要给小儿子娶媳妇，不把她嫁了就没有钱做聘礼，所以把她许给了贺家墺的贺老六。祥林嫂回家之后，她婆婆就逼她上轿。 As it turned out, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife had left for work without telling her mother-in-law. Her mother-in-law wanted to find a wife for her younger son, and without the income from marrying her off they could not afford to pay the bride price. Xianglin's wife was thus promised to He Laoliu of Hejia Village. After Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife came home, her mother-in-law forced her to enter the bridal sedan chair.</description></item><item><title>Page 18</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-18/</guid><description>他们穿过热闹的市场，彼帝加只有一个念头：跑掉！他的心思被警察看透了：&amp;ldquo;想溜到吗？那就跑吧！&amp;ldquo;可他却一本正经的说：&amp;ldquo;我才不跑呢！即使打死我，我也不跑。&amp;rdquo; As they crossed the lively market, Petka only had one thought: &amp;ldquo;Run away!&amp;rdquo; The policeman read his mind. &amp;ldquo;Want to slip away? Just run away then!&amp;rdquo; But he answered seriously: &amp;ldquo;I won&amp;rsquo;t run away! Even if you beat me to death, I won&amp;rsquo;t run away.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 18</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-18/</guid><description>孩子们都上了岸，眼巴巴的看着这个大西瓜。泥鳅从小洞里看见他们害怕的样子，不由得想笑。 The children all went ashore, looking anxiously at the huge watermelon. Niqiu watched their frightened expressions through the small holes in the watermelon and could not help wanting to laugh.</description></item><item><title>Page 18</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-18/</guid><description>祥林嫂不依，她婆婆就叫小儿子把她用绳子一捆，塞在花轿里。祥林嫂一路只是嚎，骂，花轿抬到贺家墺， 她喉咙已经全哑了。 Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife would not comply, so her mother-in-law told the younger son to tie her up with a rope and shove her into the sedan chair. Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife howled and cursed the whole way, so by the time they arrived at Hejia Village, she was completely hoarse.</description></item><item><title>Page 19</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-19/</guid><description>警察走得口渴了，正好跟过一个叫 &amp;ldquo;米兰&amp;rdquo; 的茶馆，他叫彼蒂加一同进去喝茶，彼蒂加不肯。警察说：&amp;ldquo;我知道你是不跑的，你是一个乖小子&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;他让彼蒂加在外边等着，自己进去了。 The policeman walked and became thirsty, just as they passed by a teahouse called &amp;ldquo;Milan&amp;rdquo;. He asked Petka to go in together to drink some tea, but Petka refused. The policeman said: &amp;ldquo;I know you won&amp;rsquo;t run away. You&amp;rsquo;re a good boy…&amp;rdquo; He left Petka waiting outside and went in by himself.</description></item><item><title>Page 19</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-19/</guid><description>他手一按，脚一踩，半个身子露出水面来。他晃着西瓜头，高兴地唱起了秧歌调。 He pushed with his hands, stomped with his feet and the upper part of his body emerged from the water. He shook his watermelon head and happily began to sing a Yangge tune.</description></item><item><title>Page 19</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-19/</guid><description>拉出轿来，贺老六的哥哥和祥林嫂的小叔子使劲的擒住她，也还拜不成天地。 After being pulled out of the sedan chair, He Laoliu&amp;rsquo;s brother and her late husband&amp;rsquo;s brother exerted all their strength to restrain her, nonetheless they still could not make her complete the kowtows of the wedding ceremony.</description></item><item><title>Page 20</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-20/</guid><description>彼蒂加二话没说拔脚就跑。他像插上了翅膀，转过街角，狂奔飞跑，心都快要从胸口里跳出来了。往哪儿去呢？他自己也不知道。 Without another word, Petka turned around and ran. He seemed to have grown wings, he turned around the corner and his heart was about to jump out of his chest. Where should he go? He did not know himself.</description></item><item><title>Page 20</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-20/</guid><description>小伙伴二嘎子听出是泥鳅的声音，便一挥手喊起来：&amp;ldquo;走哇！打这个大头鬼！&amp;rdquo; 于是十几个孩子一齐跳下水，朝泥鳅追去。 When Little Ergazi recognized Niqiu&amp;rsquo;s voice, he waved his hand and shouted: &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s go! Beat this big-headed ghost!&amp;rdquo; Following that, a dozen children collectively jumped into the water and chased after Niqiu.</description></item><item><title>Page 20</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-20/</guid><description>他们一不小心，一松手，祥林嫂就一头撞在香案角上，头上碰了一个大窟窿，鲜血直流，用了两把香灰,包上两块红布还止不住血。 When they, for a second, accidentally loosened their grip, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife rammed her head into the corner of the incense burner table. She struck a large hole into her head, and fresh blood was flowing. They put two handfuls of incense ash on the wound and wrapped it with two pieces of red cloth, but they still could not stop the blood flow.</description></item><item><title>Page 21</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-21/</guid><description>他终于在街市的尽头站住了。回头望望没有人追踪，心想：到底跑掉了! 现在我自由了! 他想起了表，用手一摸，哎呀! 表不在了，连袋子也没了。他灰心丧气，差一点哭出来。 Finally, he stopped at the end of the market. He turned around and saw that no one was following him, thinking: &amp;ldquo;In the end I got away! Now I&amp;rsquo;m free!&amp;rdquo; He remembered the watch and felt for it. OH NO! The watch was gone, even his pocket had disappeared. He was so disheartened that he almost began to cry.</description></item><item><title>Page 21</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-21/</guid><description>一群孩子对付泥鳅一个人，在水里打起水仗来。烂泥从四面八方向他扔来，打得西瓜皮咚咚直响，泥鳅转着圈儿迎击。 It was a bunch of kids against Niqiu alone, starting a battle in the water. Mud was thrown at Niqiu from all directions, hitting the watermelon skin with a thud. Niqiu, spinning in circles, retaliated.</description></item><item><title>Page 21</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-21/</guid><description>直到他们七手八脚地将她和贺老六反关在新房里，她还是骂。 Even when they, with many other people lending hands, finally managed to lock her and He Laoliu up in the bridal chamber, she still kept on cursing.</description></item><item><title>Page 22</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-22/</guid><description>他循着原路回去找，可连表的影子也没看到。快到&amp;quot;米兰&amp;quot;茶馆时，他的眼睛突然一亮，马路上躺着装着表的袋子，他弯腰拾起袋子，哈! 表还在呢! He went back the same way, but he did not even see a shadow of his watch. When he had almost reached the &amp;ldquo;Milan&amp;rdquo; teahouse, his eyes suddenly brightened, as he saw the pocket with the watch in it. He bent down to pick it up. HA! The watch was still there!</description></item><item><title>Page 22</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-22/</guid><description>打了一阵，泥鳅使了个空城计，他悄悄地把头从瓜皮里退出来，一个猛子扎到大苇塘里，掏水鸟蛋去了，他的小伙伴们还向瓜皮上扔泥呢。 After fighting for a while, Niqiu made a feint. He carefully backed his head away from the watermelon, rapidly went into the big reed pond and went to dig for waterbird eggs. His comrades were still throwing mud at the watermelon skin.</description></item><item><title>Page 22</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-22/</guid><description>后来，祥林嫂到底拗不过，这才依顺了。贺老六有的是力气，会做活，房子是自家的，上头又没有婆婆，别人都说她交了好运。到年底，她就生了一个胖儿子，取名阿毛。 At last, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife was unable to resist any longer, and she obeyed. He Laoliu had strength, he could work, the house was his family&amp;rsquo;s, and there was no mother-in-law over her head, so others said that she hit the jackpot. At the end of the year, she gave birth to a plump son named Ah Mao.</description></item><item><title>Page 23</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-23/</guid><description>这时警察从茶馆里出来了：&amp;ldquo;好！你毕竟等着，真是好样儿的！&amp;ldquo;他拿出一块甜饼递给彼蒂加。随后，他们继续向教养院走去。 Right at that moment, the policeman stepped out of the teahouse: &amp;ldquo;Good! You&amp;rsquo;ve waited after all. What a good boy!&amp;rdquo; He took out a piece of sweet cake and handed it to Petka. After this, they continued their walk to the reformatory.</description></item><item><title>Page 23</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-23/</guid><description>忽然坑西边有人大声喊：&amp;ldquo;敌人来啦！&amp;ldquo;孩子们一听，赶忙上岸钻进了高粱地。 Suddenly, someone screamed from the west of the pond: &amp;ldquo;The enemies are coming!&amp;rdquo; As soon as the children heard that, they hurriedly went ashore and slipped into the sorghum field.</description></item><item><title>Page 23</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-23/</guid><description>不料过了三年，贺老六染上伤寒症，本来已经好了的，吃了一碗冷饭，复发了，年纪青青的丧了命。 Unexpectedly, after three years, He Laoliu caught typhoid fever. He had already recovered, but after eating a bowl of cold rice, he relapsed and died at a young age.</description></item><item><title>Page 24</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-24/</guid><description>不多时，他们来到教养院。教养院的房子全是绿顶白墙，窗户带着罩窗，还有个院子，右头围墙，一重大门。彼蒂加叹了一口气。他想，这监牢似的教养院，谁能从这儿逃走呢? Before long, they arrived at the reformatory. The building of the reformatory had a green roof and white walls. The windows had curtains and there was a yard. On the right side of the fence, there was a heavy gate. Petka sighed. He thought: &amp;ldquo;This reformatory is like a prison, who can escape from here?&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 24</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-24/</guid><description>泥鳅正在苇塘里掏水鸟蛋，离坑沿远，耳朵眼里又塞着秫秸芯，没有听见喊声。等他出了苇塘一看，哟！人都哪儿去了呢？水坑里只有那个西瓜皮还漂在水面上。 In the reed pond Niqiu was digging for water bird eggs, far away from the edge of the pond, and since his ears and eyes were filled with sorghum sticks, he did not hear the shout. When he got out of the reed and looked around, he thought: &amp;ldquo;Oh! Where is everyone?&amp;rdquo; Only the watermelon skin was still floating on the surface of the water.</description></item><item><title>Page 24</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-24/</guid><description>祥林嫂打柴，摘茶， 养蚕，苦苦的扶养着儿子阿毛。 Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife gathered firewood, plucked tea, raised silkworms, struggling to raise her son Ah Mao.</description></item><item><title>Page 25</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-25/</guid><description>警察叫开门，他们走进二楼去见院长。警察向院长要了收据，看了彼蒂加一眼：&amp;ldquo;孩子好好地在这儿生活吧！再见!&amp;rdquo; The policeman called to open the door and they went to the second floor to see the director. The policeman requested for a receipt from the director and glanced at Petka: &amp;ldquo;Child, live well here! Goodbye!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 25</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-25/</guid><description>他上了西岸，站直了身子，看了看自己的影子，影子还矮着哩。心想：&amp;ldquo;还不到下半晌，为什么都走了？&amp;rdquo; He got onto the west bank, stood up straight and looked at his shadow which was still short. He thought: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not yet afternoon, why did they all leave?&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 25</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-25/</guid><description>第二年春天，这一日，祥林嫂一清早起来就开了门，拿小篮盛了一篮豆，叫阿毛坐在门槛上剥豆子。 One day in the following spring, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife opened the door early in the morning, scooped a basketful of beans into a small basket, and called Ah Mao to sit at the threshold and shell beans.</description></item><item><title>Page 26</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-26/</guid><description>院长一边翻看着警察局的公文，一边对彼蒂加说：&amp;ldquo;哦，小偷？这干不得！你这小，再边几年就能成为一个有用的人了&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;现在我们首先得整理你的外表。&amp;rdquo; While the director looked through the police documents, he turned to Petka: &amp;ldquo;Oh, a thief? This can&amp;rsquo;t be! You&amp;rsquo;re still young, in a few years, you can turn into a useful person&amp;hellip; now, we first have to put your appearance in order.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 26</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-26/</guid><description>他抖掉头上的水，正在坑沿上四下张望，一个乡亲从西往东跑过来，向后指着对泥鳅说：&amp;ldquo;快跑！汉奸队又来啦！&amp;rdquo; He shook the water off his head and looked around the edge of the pond when a villager came running past from west to east, pointing backwards and saying to Niqiu: &amp;ldquo;Run away! The traitors are returning!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 26</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-26/</guid><description>她自己就在屋后劈柴，淘米，米下了锅，要蒸豆了，她这才叫阿毛。 She herself was at the back of the house chopping firewood and rinsing rice. After putting the rice into the pot, it was time to steam the beans, and only then did she call Ah Mao.</description></item><item><title>Page 27</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-27/</guid><description>彼蒂加被带到卫生科。卫生员叫他把衣服脱光进浴盆洗澡，还要把他的破衣服烧掉，换一身新的。 Petka was taken to the infirmary. The health worker told him to take off all his clothes, to take a bath in the bathtub and to burn his worn-out clothes in exchange for a set of new ones.</description></item><item><title>Page 27</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-27/</guid><description>泥鳅听了，手一扳树杈，就上了坑沿那棵弯弯的老柳树，手打眼罩往西一看，十几个伪军，正顺着小路往这边走。 When Niqiu heard this, he grabbed a tree branch and pulled himself up onto the curved old willow tree at the pond. Using his hand as a visor, he looked westwards and saw a dozen or so puppet soldiers walking along a small path towards him.</description></item><item><title>Page 27</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-27/</guid><description>没有应，她出来一看，只见豆撒得一地，没有她的阿毛了。 When there was no response, she went outside to look. All that could be seen were beans scattered all over the ground. Her Ah Mao was gone.</description></item><item><title>Page 28</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-28/</guid><description>彼蒂加吃了一惊。他紧紧抓住裤子，怎么办呢？表&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;幸运的是卫生员暂时离开了浴室。他来不及多想，迅速地从口袋里掏出表，把它塞进嘴里。 Petka was shocked. He firmly held on to his trousers: &amp;ldquo;What should I do? The watch&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Fortunately, the health worker left the bathroom for a moment. He did not have much time to think, so he quickly took the watch out of his pocket and put it in his mouth.</description></item><item><title>Page 28</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-28/</guid><description>那个老乡叫他快走，泥鳅看了看瓜地，咬了咬嘴唇说：&amp;ldquo;大叔你走吧，我还要看瓜！&amp;ldquo;那个老乡说：&amp;ldquo;看瓜？这可不是闹着玩的！上回那些坏蛋来，吃了瓜还把张大爷打了一顿。&amp;rdquo; The villager told him to run away, but Niqiu looked at the melon patch, bit his lip and said: &amp;ldquo;You go ahead, Uncle! I need to watch over the melons!&amp;rdquo; The villager answered: &amp;ldquo;Watch over the melons? This is not a joke! Last time those bastards came, they ate the melons and beat up Uncle Zhang.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 28</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-28/</guid><description>她各处去问，都没有，她急了，央人出去寻。 She asked around everywhere, but no one had seen him. She became worried, and begged people to go search for him.</description></item><item><title>Page 29</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-29/</guid><description>卫生员来了，他用钳子把彼蒂加的脏衣服夹了出来，然后又回来给他洗澡。彼蒂加已经五年没洗澡了，躺在浴盆里感到舒服极了。卫生员问他问这问那。彼蒂加因为嘴里含着表，一句话也说不出，只是点头或摇头。 The health worker came back. He carried Petka&amp;rsquo;s clothes outside with pliers, then returned to give him a bath. Petka had not taken a bath in five years, so when he lay in the bathtub, it felt really comfortable. The health worker asked a stream of questions. But because Petka had the watch in his mouth, he could not say a word, he just nodded or shook his head.</description></item><item><title>Page 29</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-29/</guid><description>一提这件事，泥鳅气就来了，他愤愤地说：&amp;ldquo;我不能让他们白吃张大爷的瓜，是谁吃的，我都给他记上，有机会，都得叫他们还帐。&amp;rdquo;
When this was mentioned, Niqiu&amp;rsquo;s anger rose again. He said angrily: &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t let them eat Uncle Zhang&amp;rsquo;s melons for free. Whoever ate them, I&amp;rsquo;ll put that on his bill, and I&amp;rsquo;ll make them pay for it when I get the chance.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 29</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-29/</guid><description>直到下半天，寻来寻去寻到山墺里，看见刺柴上挂着一只阿毛的小鞋。大家都说：&amp;ldquo;糟了，怕是遭了狼了。&amp;rdquo; Until the afternoon, they searched all over and reached a mountain clearing, where they saw one of Ah Mao&amp;rsquo;s little shoes hanging on a thorny branch. They all said: &amp;ldquo;Oh no, it looks like a wolf got him.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 30</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-30/</guid><description>卫生员终于关上了他的话匣子。他放掉脏水，又放进干净的水，然后拿起报纸：&amp;ldquo;孩子，如果太冷或太热，你就说话。&amp;rdquo; The health worker finally turned off his chatterbox. He let the dirty water out, and filled it up with clean water, then he took the newspapers: &amp;ldquo;Kid, if it&amp;rsquo;s too cold or too hot, just tell me.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 30</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-30/</guid><description>那位老乡见劝不动他，只好走了。泥鳅抓住一条树枝一悠，&amp;ldquo;扑通&amp;quot;一声，就扎到水里，把西瓜皮又套到了头上，站在没脖儿深的水里。 The villager saw that Niqiu could not be persuaded, so he could only walk away. Niqiu grabbed a long tree branch, swung himself and - SPLASH - plunged into the water. He put the watermelon skin on his head again and stood in the water which did not reach his neck.</description></item><item><title>Page 30</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-30/</guid><description>再寻进去，阿毛果然躺在草窠里，肚里的五脏已经都给狼吃空了，手上还紧紧地捏着那只小蓝。 Continuing the search, they indeed found Ah Mao lying in a grassy den, his guts already eaten away by the wolf. His hand was still tightly grasping the small basket.</description></item><item><title>Page 31</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-31/</guid><description>热水不断地从龙头里涌出，浴盆里渐渐地烫起来，彼蒂加焦急不安地折腾开了，却又说不出话来。最后，他实在熬不住了，一下子把表吐在浴盆里，大叫一声：&amp;ldquo;烫呀!&amp;ldquo;并像弹簧似的跳了出来。 The hot water gushed from the tap ceaselessly. The water in the bathtub got hotter and hotter. Petka tossed about uneasily but was unable to speak out. In the end, he could not take it anymore. All of a sudden, he spit the watch into the bathtub, and screamed: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s boiling!&amp;rdquo; and jumped out like a metal spring.</description></item><item><title>Page 31</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-31/</guid><description>一会儿，便衣队特务和两个伪军来到西瓜地里，满地里找西瓜，也没找到一个熟的，他们气的把瓜秧全给拔了，生西瓜蛋踢得满地乱滚。 After a while, a plain clothes spy and two puppet soldiers came to the watermelon patch and searched the whole ground for melons but could not find a single ripe one. They became so angry that they pulled up all the melon seedlings and kicked the unripe melons all over the place.</description></item><item><title>Page 31</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-31/</guid><description>现在，祥林嫂只剩了一个光身了。 Now, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife was left with nothing but her lone self.</description></item><item><title>Page 32</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-32/</guid><description>卫生员又放了许多冷水在浴盆里，彼蒂加又重新跳了进去。他急忙在盆底摸表，终于碰到了光滑的圆东西，他惊喜地又把它塞进嘴里。不知为什么，浴盆里的水在逐渐减少。 The health worker then poured cold water into the bathtub, so Petka jumped in again. He anxiously felt for the watch at the bottom of the bathtub and finally got hold of a smooth round thing. He eagerly put it into his mouth again. He did not know why, but the water in the bathtub became less and less.</description></item><item><title>Page 32</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-32/</guid><description>糟踏了一阵，他们站在坑沿上，用高粱叶子作扇子，扇着体息，口渴得直舐嘴唇。 After trampling for a while, they stood on the edge of the pond and used sorghum leaves as fans. Fanning, they rested and licked their lips with thirst.</description></item><item><title>Page 32</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-32/</guid><description>到秋天，贺老六的哥哥竟来收屋，把她赶了出来。 When autumn came, He Laoliu&amp;rsquo;s older brother took over the house and threw her.</description></item><item><title>Page 33</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-33/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-33/</guid><description>洗完澡，卫生员给他一套新衣服。他第一次穿这么漂亮的衣服，乐得咧着嘴笑了。卫生员诧导地看着他嘴里发亮的东西：&amp;ldquo;这是什么？&amp;rdquo; When he was done bathing, the health worker gave him a set of new clothes. It was the first time for him to wear such pretty clothes, so he grinned with his mouth wide open. The health worker was surprised to see something shiny in his mouth: &amp;ldquo;What is this?&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 33</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-33/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-33/</guid><description>那个高个子的伪军忽然向坑里指着说：&amp;ldquo;大西瓜！&amp;ldquo;小个儿马上说：&amp;ldquo;是我先看见的！&amp;ldquo;两个伪军争着要脱衣服下水去捞。 Suddenly, the tall puppet soldier pointed at the pond and said: &amp;ldquo;Look at the huge watermelon!&amp;rdquo; The short one immediately replied: &amp;ldquo;I saw it first!&amp;rdquo; The two puppet soldiers vied to undress in order to get into the water and fish it out.</description></item><item><title>Page 33</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-33/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-33/</guid><description>祥林嫂走投无路，只好拎了一只荸荠式的圆篮，一个小铺盖，又到鲁镇来找卫老婆子。 Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife had nowhere to go, carrying around a basket shaped like a water chestnut and a small bedroll, she came again to Luzhen looking for Old Wei.</description></item><item><title>Page 34</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-34/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-34/</guid><description>彼蒂加赶紧闭上嘴，卫生员哪肯放过。最后，彼蒂加只得把它吐出来。天啊！这不是浴盆的铜塞子吗？卫生员惊奇地问：&amp;ldquo;告诉我，为什么把它放进嘴里？&amp;ldquo;彼蒂加只好撤谎：&amp;ldquo;我饿！&amp;rdquo; Petka hastily closed his mouth, but the health worker would not let go. In the end, Petka had to spit it out. Good heavens! Was this not the copper plug of the bathtub? The health worker was surprised: &amp;ldquo;Tell me, why did you put that into your mouth?&amp;rdquo; Petka had to lie: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m hungry!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 34</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-34/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-34/</guid><description>那个便衣特务呲着满嘴金牙得意地说：&amp;ldquo;你们俩谁也别抢，是我先看见的。&amp;ldquo;说着，就抢先穿着肥大的灯笼裤下了水。 The spy bared his mouth full of gold teeth and said complacently: &amp;ldquo;Neither of you snatch it, I saw it first.&amp;rdquo; As he was speaking, he rushed into the water in his loosely fitting knickerbockers.</description></item><item><title>Page 34</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-34/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-34/</guid><description>卫老婆子又将她带来鲁四老爷家里来了。四太太踌踌了一会，便叫祥林嫂拿圆篮和铺盖到下房去。四老爷照例皱皱眉，但鉴于向来雇用女工之难，也就并不大反对。 Old Wei brought her to Mr. Lu&amp;rsquo;s house again. His wife hesitated for a while, but eventually told Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife to bring her basket and bedroll to the servant&amp;rsquo;s room. Mr. Lu frowned as usual, but in view of the difficulty of employing female workers, he did not oppose.</description></item><item><title>Page 35</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-35/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-35/</guid><description>表哪去了？彼蒂加偷偷朝浴盆张望。浴盆里水已流净，只有一块浴巾。卫生员把铜塞子扔回浴盆，去拿浴巾。彼蒂加心想：这可惜了！表一定在浴巾下面。他灵机一动，突然大叫起来：&amp;ldquo;啊唷！肚子痛！&amp;rdquo; Where did the watch go? Petka secretly peeped towards the bathtub. The water in the bathtub had already drained away, there was only a washcloth left. The health worker threw the plug back into the bathtub and was about to take the washcloth. Petka thought: &amp;ldquo;Too bad! The watch must be under the towel.&amp;rdquo; He had a sudden idea and screamed: &amp;ldquo;Ouch! My stomach is aching!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 35</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-35/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-35/</guid><description>岸上两个伪军气得撅着嘴说：&amp;ldquo;这坑水可深，小心淹死你。&amp;ldquo;便衣特务得意地说：&amp;ldquo;老子淹不死。这是种瓜的老头特意为我留的，要不是上次教训了他一顿，今天他能给我留吗？&amp;rdquo; Pouting with anger, the two puppet soldiers on the bank said: &amp;ldquo;That pond is really deep, be careful not to drown.&amp;rdquo; The spy said proudly: &amp;ldquo;I won&amp;rsquo;t drown. The old man who grows melons reserved this one especially for me. If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t taught him a lesson last time, would he have saved one for me today?&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 35</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-35/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-35/</guid><description>四老爷只是暗暗告诫四太太说，祥林嫂这种人虽然似乎很可怜，但是败坏风俗，用她帮忙还可以，祭祀时候可用不着她沾手，否则，不干不净，祖宗不是吃的。 Mr. Lu cautioned his wife in private, that although someone like Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife seems pitiful, she exerts a bad moral influence. It is okay to use her help, but she should not lend a hand during the sacrifices. Otherwise, the ancestors would not eat on because of her taints.</description></item><item><title>Page 36</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-36/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-36/</guid><description>卫生员慌了，急忙奔出门去取药。彼蒂加扑到浴巾上，一点不错，表就躺在浴巾下面。他急忙把它抓在手里，把水擦干，欣赏着。手心里的表活像是太阳在放光。 The health worker panicked and hurried out the door to get some medicine. Petka launched towards the cloth. And indeed!, the watch was really under the cloth. He grabbed it really fast, wiped it dry, and admired it. The watch in his hands was shining like the sun.</description></item><item><title>Page 36</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-36/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-36/</guid><description>泥鳅见便衣特务朝自己走来，水圈一环环地从他脖子上涌过，他看到特务那个不会水的样子，想起了&amp;quot;千斤牛入水，斗不过大鲤鱼&amp;quot;，就壮起了胆。 Niqiu saw the spy coming towards him, ripples on the water around his neck. Upon realizing that the spy could not swim well, he recalled the saying: &amp;ldquo;When thousand pounds of cattle enter the water, they cannot defeat a carp&amp;rdquo;, and mustered up his courage.</description></item><item><title>Page 36</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-36/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-36/</guid><description>鲁四老爷家里最重大的事件是祭祀，祥林嫂先前最忙的时候也就是祭祀，这回她却清闲了。桌子放在堂中央，她去分配酒杯和筷子。四太太慌忙地说：&amp;ldquo;祥林嫂， 你放着罢！我来摆。&amp;rdquo; Sacrificing to the ancestors was the biggest event for the family of Mr. Lu. Previously, the sacrifices were also the busiest time for Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife. This time, however, she had nothing to do. The table was set in the centre of the hall, and she went to distribute glasses and chopsticks. Mrs. Lu rushed to say: &amp;ldquo;Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife, leave it there! I&amp;rsquo;ll do it.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 37</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-37/</guid><description>彼蒂加急忙把表装进崭新的裤袋里。这时，卫生员拿来一瓶阿摩尼亚水，他嗅了嗅，打了几个喷嚏，就装作病好了。经过梳洗打扮，他变成一个漂亮的小伙子了。 Petka hastily put the watch into the pocket of his brand-new pants. Right then, the health worker brought a bottle of ammonia solution. Petka sniffed it, sneezed a few times, and then pretended to be cured. Now that he had freshened up, he turned into a pretty young lad.</description></item><item><title>Page 37</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-37/</guid><description>特务晃晃悠悠地蹚着水向西瓜走来，高兴得鼻子眼睛全挤在一块了。眼看就快要够到手了，突然&amp;quot;妈呀！&amp;ldquo;一声不见了。 The spy wiggled and waded towards the watermelon and squeezed his nose and eyes in happiness. As he was reaching for the melon, a sudden &amp;ldquo;Oh my!&amp;rdquo; was followed by an abrupt silence.</description></item><item><title>Page 37</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-37/</guid><description>她只好缩了手，又去取烛台，四太太慌忙地说：&amp;ldquo;祥林嫂，你放着罢！我来拿。&amp;rdquo; She was forced to withdraw her hand and went to pick up a candlestick. Mrs. Lu said in a panic: &amp;ldquo;Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife, leave it there! I&amp;rsquo;ll get it.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 38</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-38/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-38/</guid><description>彼蒂加来到食堂，饭菜又热又香。他贪婪地吃着，连盘子都舔光了。独眼龙毕塔珂夫逗弄起他来了：&amp;ldquo;大饭桶，比大象吃得还多！&amp;ldquo;彼蒂加生气了，把匙子掷过去，正敲在独眼龙的脑门上。 When Petka arrived at the canteen, the food was hot and smelled good. He ate greedily, even licking the plate clean. The one-eyed Pyatakov began to tease him: &amp;ldquo;You greedy pig! You eat more than an elephant!&amp;rdquo; Petka became angry and threw his spoon right at One Eye&amp;rsquo;s forehead.</description></item><item><title>Page 38</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-38/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-38/</guid><description>两个伪军以为这小子故意装的，高个子伪军说：&amp;ldquo;别得了便宜卖乘，没人跟你抢！&amp;ldquo;小个子伪军看着冒出水面的水泡说：&amp;ldquo;上来吧，别在那吐泡了！&amp;rdquo; The two puppet soldiers thought he was just pretending, so the tall one said: &amp;ldquo;Stop acting, no one's going to fight you for it!&amp;rdquo; Watching the bubbles rise up to the surface, the short one said: &amp;ldquo;Come on up, stop blowing bubbles there!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 38</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-38/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-38/</guid><description>她转了几个圆圈，终于没有事情做，只得疑惑的走开。她在这一天可做的事只不过坐在灶下烧火。 After making a few rounds around the house, finally, there was nothing left for her to do but to walk away in confusion. All she could do on this day was to sit by the stove and tend to the fire.</description></item><item><title>Page 39</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-39/</guid><description>出了乱子了，院长赶来了。他用严厉的目光看着彼蒂加：&amp;ldquo;站到门口去，直到大家吃完午饭为止！&amp;rdquo; 孩子们吃完午饭，三三两两从彼蒂加面前跑过去，有的向他伸舌头，有的向他扮鬼脸。 Upon the commotion, the director rushed in. He gave Petka a stern look: &amp;ldquo;Stand in the doorway until everybody has finished their lunch!&amp;rdquo; After the children had finished their lunch, they ran past Petka in groups of twos and threes, some of them sticking out their tongues, some of them making faces at him.</description></item><item><title>Page 39</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-39/</guid><description>半袋烟的功夫过去了，特务也没露面。这时两个伪军才觉察到出了事。高个子让小个子先下去看看，小个子说：&amp;ldquo;瓜是你先看见的，应该你先下去。&amp;ldquo;他俩谁也不敢下去，只在岸上乱叫。 They smoked half a pack of cigarettes, yet the spy did not reappear. Only now, the two soldiers realized that something was wrong. The tall one ordered the small one to go down first and take a look, but the small one said: &amp;ldquo;You saw the melon first, so you should be the one to go down there first.&amp;rdquo; Neither of them dared to go down, they just stood at the bank and shouted.</description></item><item><title>Page 39</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-39/</guid><description>镇上的人们仍然叫她祥林嫂，但音调和先前很不同；也还和她讲话，但笑容却冷冷的了。她全不理会那些事，只是直着眼睛，和大家讲她的儿子遭狼的故事，讲完就淌下眼泪来，声音也呜咽了。 Townspeople still called her Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife, but the tone was very different from before. They still talked with her, but their smiles had turned cold. She ignored those things, and with straight eyes she told everyone the story of how her son had been attacked by a wolf. When she finished her tale, she shed tears and her voice choked with sobs.</description></item><item><title>Page 40</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-40/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-40/</guid><description>傍晚，彼蒂加担心把表带在身上会出乱子，于是来到院子里，在墙根挖了个小坑。他把表包好，埋在小坑里，还插上一根小树枝，免得记错了地方。 At dusk, Petka worried that keeping the watch on him might cause trouble, so he went to the yard and dug a small hole at the foot of a wall. He wrapped up the watch, buried it and stuck a small twiglet on it in order not to remember the wrong spot.</description></item><item><title>Page 40</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-40/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-40/</guid><description>再说泥鳅把那个特务拖下水去灌饱之后，就拉着他的腿绕过菱角坑，荷花塘，一口气把他拖到了大苇塘里。 After Niqiu dragged the spy down into the water to fill him up, he pulled him by the legs around the water chestnut pond, the lotus pond, and the big reed pond in one go.</description></item><item><title>Page 40</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-40/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-40/</guid><description>这故事倒颇有效，男人听了，往往收起笑容，没趣的走开了；女人们却像宽恕了她似的，脸上立刻改换了鄙薄的神气，还要陪出许多眼泪来。 This story worked quite effectively. The men would stop smiling and walk away uninterestedly after they heard it. The women would seem to forgive her, immediately changing the contemptuous looks on their faces, and shedding tears along with her.
 </description></item><item><title>Page 41</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-41/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-41/</guid><description>当天空布满星星的时候，就寝钟响了。彼蒂加倒在床上直睡到天亮。&amp;ldquo;起来！快起来！&amp;ldquo;院长摇着他的肩膀，&amp;ldquo;警察局长要你去一趟。&amp;ldquo;彼蒂加慌神啦，脚怎么也伸不进裤脚里去。 When the sky was full of stars, the bell rang. Petka fell into bed and slept till dawn. &amp;ldquo;Get up! Get up!&amp;rdquo; The director shook his shoulder. &amp;ldquo;The chief wants you to come.&amp;rdquo; Petka panicked and could not get his feet into his trousers no matter how hard he tried.</description></item><item><title>Page 41</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-41/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-41/</guid><description>特务躺在苇塘中间的一个小土岗上，肚子鼓的活象个大气蛤蟆。泥鳅气喘吁吁地蹲在一边，一时不知该怎么办好。他想把这家伙再推下水去，又一想，留着他，抗日政府可能能从他身上了解点敌人的情况。 The spy laid on a small hill in the middle of the reed pond. His big belly resembled a huge toad. Breathing heavily, Niqiu sat next to him. All of a sudden, he did not know what to do. He wanted to drag the guy back into the water, but thought it over. He could leave him so that the anti-Japanese government might learn something about the situation of the enemy from him.</description></item><item><title>Page 41</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-41/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-41/</guid><description>她就只是反复的向人说她悲惨的故事，倘一看见两三岁的小孩子，她就想引出她的阿毛的故事来，说：&amp;ldquo;唉唉！我们的阿毛如果还在，也就有这么大了。&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; She just kept telling people again and again about her tragedy. Whenever she saw a two- or three-year-old child, she would bring up the story about her Ah-mao, and say, &amp;ldquo;Ah ah! If our Ah-mao were still alive, he would be around that age…&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 42</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-42/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-42/</guid><description>彼蒂加被带到警察局长办公室。他看见局长身旁站着一个红鼻子老汉。彼蒂加想，这一定是那个醉汉了。&amp;ldquo;凭良心回答，你偷了库兑耶尔的表吗？&amp;ldquo;局长问。&amp;ldquo;我敢赌咒，我从来没有见过表&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;彼蒂加坦然地回答。 Petka was taken to the chief&amp;rsquo;s office. He saw an old, red-nosed man standing next to the chief. Petka thought this was for sure the drunkard. &amp;ldquo;Answer honestly, did you steal Kudeyar&amp;rsquo;s watch?&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; the chief asked. &amp;ldquo;I swear, I've never seen that watch&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;, Petka answered calmly. s</description></item><item><title>Page 42</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-42/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-42/</guid><description>于是，泥鳅找了一块破碗碴儿，把特务的牙给撬了个缝，一股黑水从牙缝里淌出来。 Then, Niqiu found a small piece of a broken bowl. With the help of this shard, wedged between the teeth of the spy, Niqiu pried open the spy&amp;rsquo;s mouth, and black water flowed out.</description></item><item><title>Page 42</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-42/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-42/</guid><description>但不久，全镇的人们几乎都能背诵她的话，一听到就烦厌得头痛，立即打断她的话，走开去了，让她张着口怔怔地站着。 But before long, almost everyone in town could recite her words. As soon as they heard it, they instantly turned very annoyed, interrupted her at once, walked away, and left her standing in a daze with her mouth hanging open.</description></item><item><title>Page 43</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-43/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-43/</guid><description>局长命令警察将彼蒂加从头到脚搜一遍。彼蒂加一点也不害怕，心里非常好笑。后来局长和库兑耶尔一齐动手，结果什么也没有搜到。 The chief ordered a policeman to search Petka from head to toe. Petka, silently finding it hilarious, was not afraid at all. Later, both the chief and Kudeyar joined in, but in the end, they could not find anything.</description></item><item><title>Page 43</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-43/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-43/</guid><description>过了一会儿，特务缓过气来了，肚子一鼓一鼓的。泥鳅一看，好像觉得特务变长了，心想：&amp;ldquo;这么大个像伙，我怎么弄得过他呢？&amp;rdquo; After a while, the spy was relieved and his stomach bulged. Niqiu had a look, and it seemed that the spy had grown bigger. Niqiu thought: &amp;ldquo;What a big guy, how did I manage to overwhelm him?&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 43</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-43/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-43/</guid><description>从此她死尸似的脸上就整日没有笑影，主人们觉得她手脚也没有先前那样灵活，口气上更有些不满了。 From then on, the smile had disappeared from her corpse-like face. Her employers found her work not as efficient as before, therefore their tone towards her became more dissatisfied.</description></item><item><title>Page 44</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-44/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-44/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;他根本就没有表。他诬赖好人！&amp;ldquo;彼蒂加对局长说。局长教训了库兑耶尔一顿。库兑耶尔放声大哭。局长命令警察把彼蒂加送回教养院。 &amp;ldquo;He doesn&amp;rsquo;t even own a watch, he&amp;rsquo;s accusing innocent people!&amp;rdquo; Petka said to the chief. The chief read Kudeyar the riot act. Kudeyar began to cry loudly. The chief ordered the policeman to take Petka back to the reformatory.</description></item><item><title>Page 44</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-44/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-44/</guid><description>泥鳅小眼睛一眨，想了个主意。他扯了一把青苇子在地上踩了，拧成了一条绳子，趁特务还没清醒过来，把他的两手捆了个结结实实。 Niqiu blinked with his small eyes and had an idea. He pulled a handful of green reeds, stepped them on the ground, twisting them into a rope. While the spy was still unconscious, he tied his hands together tightly.</description></item><item><title>Page 44</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-44/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-44/</guid><description>转眼又到了年底，腊月二十以后，鲁四老爷家里又要忙着过新年了，这回另叫柳妈做帮手。柳妈是善女人，吃素，不肯杀鸡宰鹅，只管洗器皿。祥林嫂除烧火之外，没有别的事，闲坐着看柳妈洗器皿。 In the blink of an eye, it was the end of another year. After the 20th day of the twelfth lunar month, the Lu household was busy with the New Year&amp;rsquo;s celebration again. This time, they found an extra help, Auntie Liu. Auntie Liu was a Buddhist vegetarian woman who refused to kill chickens and geese, but merely washed the vessels. Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife had nothing to do except tend the fire, so she sat idly watching Auntie Liu wash the vessels.</description></item><item><title>Page 45</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-45/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-45/</guid><description>警察对彼蒂加说：&amp;ldquo;你一个人回去吧，我对你的诚实深信不疑。&amp;ldquo;彼蒂加真的一个人向教养院走去。现在他是不肯逃走的了，因为他心爱的表还埋在教养院的院子里呢！ The policeman said to Petka: &amp;ldquo;Go back by yourself, you are an honest boy.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; And Petka indeed started to walk back to the reformatory. He did not want to run away now because his beloved watch was still buried in the yard of the reformatory!</description></item><item><title>Page 45</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-45/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-45/</guid><description>特务醒过来了，他在地上直打滚。泥鳅命令他：&amp;ldquo;不准动！&amp;ldquo;特务一见是个孩子，就假装求饶说：&amp;ldquo;老弟，放开我吧！&amp;rdquo; The spy woke up and rolled back and forth on the ground. Niqiu commanded: &amp;ldquo;Freeze!&amp;rdquo; When the spy realized that Niqiu was just a child, he pretended to ask for forgiveness and said, &amp;ldquo;Little one, set me free!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 45</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-45/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-45/</guid><description>柳妈看着祥林嫂说：&amp;ldquo;你和你第二个男人过活不到两年，倒落了一件罪名。你将来到阴司去，那两个死鬼的男人还要争， 你给谁好呢？阎罗大王只好把你锯开来，分给他们。&amp;rdquo; Auntie Liu looked at Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife and said: &amp;ldquo;You and your second husband were together for less than two years, yet you are guilty of a great sin. When you arrive in the nether world, the ghosts of those two husbands will fight, whom will you be given to? The great king Yama will have to saw you apart and divide you between them.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 46</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-46/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-46/</guid><description>忽然，库兑耶尔从后面追了上来，扑倒在他的脚上：&amp;ldquo;求求你，还我表吧！我的女人在生病，孩子在挨饿。看上帝面上，还给我！&amp;rdquo; Suddenly, Kudeyar caught up with him and threw himself at his feet: &amp;ldquo;I beg you, give me back my watch! My wife is sick, the children are starving. In the name of God, give it back to me!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 46</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-46/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-46/</guid><description>泥鳅气愤地指着他说：&amp;ldquo;谁叫你当汉奸欺侮中国人哪？谁叫你抢了张大爷的瓜？&amp;ldquo;特务赶忙说：&amp;ldquo;吃瓜我给钱，快给我解开，我好给你掏钱。&amp;rdquo; Niqiu pointed at him furiously and said, &amp;ldquo;Who told you to become a traitor and bully the Chinese people? Who told you to rob Uncle Zhang's melons?&amp;rdquo; The spy answered in a rush: &amp;ldquo;I'll pay for the melon, untie me quickly, so that I can pay you.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 46</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-46/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-46/</guid><description>她听了柳吗的话，脸上就显出恐怖的神色来。柳吗接着说：&amp;ldquo;我想，你不如及早抵当。你到土地庙里。去捐一条门槛，当作你的替身，给千人踏，万人跨，赎了这一世的罪名，免得死了去受苦。&amp;rdquo; When she heard Auntie Liu&amp;rsquo;s words, a look of horror appeared on her face. Auntie Liu continued: &amp;ldquo;I think, it would be better if you go to compensate for it as soon as possible. Go to the Temple of the Village God. Donate a threshold, make it as your substitute, let thousands of people step on it, let tens of thousands of people cross over it in order to atone for your sins in life, so that you will not have to suffer in death.</description></item><item><title>Page 47</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-47/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-47/</guid><description>彼蒂加毫不理会，继续往前走。库兑耶尔从后面追上来嚷着：&amp;ldquo;我控告你！我给你吃官司！&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;告去就是了，谁也不会相信你这个老酒鬼！&amp;ldquo;彼蒂加觉得很开心，只管自己的路。 Petka did not pay him any attention and continued to walk ahead. Kudeyar caught up with him, yelling: &amp;ldquo;I will sue you! I will file a lawsuit!&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; - &amp;ldquo;Go ahead and sue me, no one will believe an old drunkard like you.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; Petka felt very happy and went his way.</description></item><item><title>Page 47</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-47/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-47/</guid><description>泥鳅笑呵呵地说：&amp;ldquo;等我把你送到抗日政府，咱俩到那再算账。&amp;ldquo;特务看软的不行，便用硬的威胁，可是毛泽东思想哺育成长起来的儿童不听这一套，威胁利诱对他们行不通。 Niqiu laughed: &amp;ldquo;Just wait until I have sent you to the anti-Japanese government, we will settle our accounts there.&amp;rdquo; When the spy saw that soft words would not work, he used hard threats, but children raised by Mao Zedong's Thought do not listen to such kinds of threats, and temptations have no effect on them.</description></item><item><title>Page 47</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-47/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-47/</guid><description>头天晚上，祥林嫂想着柳妈的话，越想越怕，到天亮才蒙胧睡去，又做了一个恶梦。第二天，早饭之后，她便到镇西头的土地庙里去求捐门槛。庙祝起初不允许，直到她急得流泪，才勉强答应了。价目是大钱十二千。 That evening, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife thought about Auntie Liu&amp;rsquo;s words, the more she thought about it the more afraid she became. Only at dawn did she fall into a hazy sleep, and even then she had a nightmare. The next day, after breakfast, she went to the Temple of the Village God at the west end of town to ask to donate a threshold. At first, the temple attendant did not give his permission, only when she shed tears out of fear did he grudgingly agree.</description></item><item><title>Page 48</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-48/</guid><description>彼蒂加打算先把表挖出来，然后翻墙逃走。可是当他一走进教养院，却看见院子里停放着许多辆运木材的大马车。孩子们在院长的指挥下，正从马车上往下搬运木材。不一会儿，木材就堆满了院子。 Petka came up with a plan. He would first dig out the watch, and then climb over the wall and run away. However, when he arrived at the reformatory, he saw that numerous horse carriages loaded with timber were parked in the courtyard. Under the command of the director, the children unloaded the logs from the carriages. Before long, the courtyard was all filled with timber.</description></item><item><title>Page 48</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-48/</guid><description>正在这时，突然&amp;quot;砰! 砰！&amp;ldquo;两声枪响，子弹飞过苇塘的上空。泥鳅赶紧趴在地上，这枪子是那两个伪军放的，他们为了壮壮胆，朝天放了两枪就走了。 At that moment &amp;ndash; BANG, BANG! &amp;ndash; suddenly two shots rang out, and the bullets flew over the reed pond. Niqiu hurriedly got down on the ground. The two puppet soldiers had fired the shots. In order to strengthen their courage, they had fired the two shots towards the sky and fled.</description></item><item><title>Page 48</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-48/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-48/</guid><description>从此，她整日紧闭了，默默的跑街，扫地，洗菜，淘米。快够一年，她才从四太太手里支取了历来积存的工钱，换算了十二元鹰洋，又请假镇西头去。 From then on, she became entirely closed off, silently walking the streets, sweeping the floor, washing vegetables and rinsing rice. It was almost a year later when she asked Mrs. Lu for her accumulated wages, adding up to 12 yuan and again took leave to go to the west end of the town.</description></item><item><title>Page 49</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-49/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-49/</guid><description>他来到埋表的地方，那上面高高地堆放着木材。&amp;ldquo;我的表&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;他伤心地哭了起来。 He arrived at the spot where he had buried the watch. Timber was piled high on top of it. &amp;ldquo;My watch&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Broken-hearted, he started to cry.</description></item><item><title>Page 49</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-49/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-49/</guid><description>忽然，泥鳅听见特务在一块石头上磨绳子，走近一看，苇绳快被特务挣断了。 Suddenly, Niqiu heard the spy grinding the rope on a rock, and when he came closer, he saw that the rope was about to be torn apart.</description></item><item><title>Page 49</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-49/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-49/</guid><description>回来的时候，她神气舒畅，眼光也分外有神，高兴似的对四太太说，她已经在土地庙捐了门槛了。 When she came home, her spirit was entirely free from worry, and her eyes were exceptionally bright, looking happy she told Mrs. Lu that she had already been at the Temple of the Village God and donated a threshold.</description></item><item><title>Page 50</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-50/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-50/</guid><description>这天夜里，他被火车的汽笛声惊醒：&amp;ldquo;唉唉，车站该是多么有趣！掏空那些有钱人的腰包多开心&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;他打定主意，今晚把表弄到手后就逃走。 At night, the sound of a train whistle woke him up. &amp;ldquo;Oh, how much fun it would be to be at the station and empty out the pockets of all those rich people&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; He made up his mind: Tonight, he would get the watch into his hands and just run away.</description></item><item><title>Page 50</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-50/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-50/</guid><description>泥鳅猛地骑在特务身上，一边用拳头打，一边狠狠地骂着。特务死命挣扎，两个人就在坑沿边滚了起来。 Niqiu violently got on top of the spy, punching him with his fists as he cursed him viciously. The spy struggled for his dear life as the two rolled around on the edge of the pond.</description></item><item><title>Page 50</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-50/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-50/</guid><description>可是到冬至的祭祖时节，祥林嫂看四太太装好祭品，便坦然去拿酒杯和筷子。不料四太太照旧慌忙地大声说：&amp;ldquo;你放着罢，祥林嫂！&amp;rdquo; When it came to the winter solstice and the sacrifices to the ancestors, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife saw Mrs. Lu preparing the sacrificial offerings and went to get the wine cups and chopsticks. But to her surprise, Mrs. Lu, as before, rushed to say: &amp;ldquo;Leave it there, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 51</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-51/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-51/</guid><description>他打开窗户，从排水管滑下来溜到院子里，来到埋表的地方。他使劲地搬开木材，一根，两根，三根&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;才搬了二三十根，他就上气不接下气了。 He opened the window, glided down the drainpipe, landed in the courtyard, and went to the place where his watch was buried. With all his strength he dragged away the logs. One log, two logs, three logs... when he had dragged away only twenty or thirty logs, he was gasping for air already.</description></item><item><title>Page 51</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-51/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-51/</guid><description>特务打不过泥鳅，就高声喊叫救命。泥鳅想堵住他的嘴，又没东西堵，特务的喊声越来越大，泥鳅怕被伪军听见，只得又把他推下水去. The spy was unable to defeat Niqiu, so he called for help. Niqiu wanted to stuff his mouth, but as he didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything, the spy&amp;rsquo;s shouting became louder and louder. Niqiu was afraid that the puppet soldiers would hear him, so he pushed him into the water again.</description></item><item><title>Page 51</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-51/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-51/</guid><description>她像是受了炮烙似的缩了手，脸色同时变作灰黑，也不再去取烛台，只是失神的站着。 She withdrew her hand as if it had been branded with red-hot metal, her face instantly became ashen, and she did not try again to fetch the candlestick, but just stood there dejectedly.</description></item><item><title>Page 52</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-52/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-52/</guid><description>当他再搬一根很重的圆木材时，一不小心滑脱了手，整个木材垛塌了下来，发出吓人的声响。随着一声嗥叫，一只大狗向他扑来。彼蒂加吓得浑身发抖，拚命地逃回宿舍里去。 Just when he was pulling one especially heavy log, it slipped out of his hands in a moment of carelessness. The entire pile of tree trunks collapsed, making a frightening noise. Following a loud growl, a huge dog jumped at Petka. Petka's entire body trembled with fear, and he ran back to the dorm for his dear life.</description></item><item><title>Page 52</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-52/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-52/</guid><description>特务在水里喝着水，象是葫芦头灌香油似的，&amp;ldquo;咕嘟嘟，咕嘟嘟&amp;rdquo;，水面上冒起了一串串水泡泡。 GLUG, GLUG &amp;ndash; The spy drank from the water like a bottle gourd from sesame oil, and a stream of bubbles rose to the surface.</description></item><item><title>Page 52</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-52/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-52/</guid><description>直到四老爷上香的时候，叫她走开，她才走开。她疑惑的想：难道自己已经在土地庙捐了门槛，还不能赎了这一世的罪名么？&amp;hellip; &amp;hellip;
Only when Mr. Lu burned the joss sticks and ordered her to leave did she leave. Feeling uncertain, she thought: Could it be that despite having already paid for a threshold in contribution to the village temple, she still could not redeem herself from the sins of this life? … </description></item><item><title>Page 53</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-53/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-53/</guid><description>第二天，彼蒂加得了严重的肺炎，整整昏睡了三个星期。 The next day, Petka came down with a serious pneumonia and slept for three weeks.</description></item><item><title>Page 53</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-53/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-53/</guid><description>敌人走后，张家庄的人都回来了，就是不见泥鳅。大伙四下里找寻着，到处都在喊着:&amp;ldquo;泥鳅！泥-------鳅--------&amp;rdquo; After the enemy had left, all the villagers of Zhangjia Village returned, but Niqiu was nowhere to be seen. Everybody was searching for him in all directions and shouted: &amp;ldquo;Niqiu! Niiiiiiqiuuuuuuuuuuu!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 53</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-53/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-53/</guid><description>这一回她的变化非常大，第二天，不但眼睛凹陷下去，连精神也更不济了，而且很胆怯，有如在白天出穴游行的小鼠；否则呆坐着简直是一个木偶人。 This time, there was a huge change in her. The next day, her eyes were sunken down, her spirit further wasted away, and she became very timid, like a mouse wandering out of its hole in daytime; on other occasions she sat blankly, like a puppet.</description></item><item><title>Page 54</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-54/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-54/</guid><description>彼蒂加终于活下来了，恢复知觉了。一天，小伙伴米罗诺夫给他送来一本画书，还告诉他，在他害病的那天，毕塔珂夫因偷木材被送到少年管教所去了。彼蒂加禁不住绯红了脸。 Petka finally started to get better and recovered his consciousness. One day, his mate Milonov brought him a picture book. He told him that Pyatakov had been sent to the youth custody centre for stealing wood on the same day that Petka had fallen ill. Petka could not help but blush.</description></item><item><title>Page 54</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-54/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-54/</guid><description>泥鳅听了，使用两手卷成个筒筒，放在嘴上，拉长声音回答说:&amp;ldquo;我在这儿哪!&amp;rdquo; When Niqiu heard them, he formed his hands to a tube, raised them to his mouth and answered: &amp;ldquo;I am heeeeeeeere!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 54</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-54/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-54/</guid><description>不到半年，她头发也花白起来了，记性尤其坏，甚而至于常常忘却了去淘米。四太太有时当面就说：&amp;ldquo;祥林嫂怎么这样了？倒不如那时不留她。&amp;ldquo;似乎是警告她，想打发她走了。 Within half a year, her hair started to turn white, her memory became particularly poor, even to the point that she frequently forgot to go and rinse rice. Mrs. Lu sometimes said right in front of her: &amp;ldquo;How come Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife becomes like this? It would have been better if we hadn&amp;rsquo;t kept her.&amp;rdquo; It was as if she was warning her that she wanted to dismiss her.</description></item><item><title>Page 55</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-55/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-55/</guid><description>米罗诺夫走后，彼蒂加很难过，心想：毕塔珂夫虽然讨厌，毕竟是自己的小伙伴，不能让他白受冤在。他决定去找院长，说明那天晚上是他搬动了木材，但埋表的事是绝对不能讲的。 After Milonov had left, Petka felt very bad and thought to himself: &amp;ldquo;Even though I detest Pyatakov, he is still my mate, and I can&amp;rsquo;t let him be accused wrongly.&amp;rdquo; He decided that he would go to the director and explain that it had been Petka himself, who had moved the logs on that very night, but he would not say a word about the watch.</description></item><item><title>Page 55</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-55/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/niqiu/b-page-55/</guid><description>泥鳅把喝饱水的特务又拖到东岸上。大伙一看，都高兴地说:&amp;ldquo;泥鳅真是共产党教育出来的好孩子，又为乡亲们除了一害！&amp;ldquo;泥鳅充满信心地表示:&amp;ldquo;要消灭这些害人虫,把日本鬼子赶出中国去！取得抗战的全部胜利！&amp;rdquo; Niqiu pulled the spy, who had had enough to drink, to the east bank. When everybody saw this, they happily said: &amp;ldquo;Niqiu is a good boy educated by the Communist Party, he averted yet another harm to the villagers!&amp;rdquo; Niqiu said with confidence: &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s destroy this vermin and drive the Japanese devils out of China! Let&amp;rsquo;s achieve total victory in the war!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 55</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-55/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-55/</guid><description>不久，四太太终于停了祥林嫂的工，叫她回到卫老婆子那里去。镇上谁家都不肯雇用她，卫老婆子也没法收留，祥林嫂就成了乞丐。她头发全白，不像四十上下的人了。 Before long, Mrs. Lu finally suspended Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife&amp;rsquo;s work and told her to return to Old Wei&amp;rsquo;s. No household in town was willing to employ her, and Old Wei was unable to take her in, so Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife became a beggar. Her hair turned completely white, and she did not look like a person in their forties anymore.</description></item><item><title>Page 56</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-56/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-56/</guid><description>可是，他来到院长办公室，却又失掉了勇气。院长问他有什么事，他只说是来向院长借画书的。院长见他喜欢读书了，很高兴，就拿给他许多书。 However, when he arrived in the director&amp;rsquo;s office, his courage left him. The director asked him what the matter was, but he only managed to say that he had come to borrow some picture books from him. When the director saw that he liked reading, he was very happy, and gave him many books.</description></item><item><title>Page 56</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-56/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-56/</guid><description>她见到识字的人，就用眼钉着问：&amp;ldquo;一个人死了之后，究竟有没有魂灵的？&amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; 死掉的一家人，真的都能见面么？&amp;hellip; &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; 但是，有谁能回答她呢！就是答得出，又能给她多少安慰呢！ When she came across someone literate, she fixed her stare at him and asked: &amp;ldquo;When a person dies, do they actually have a soul? &amp;hellip; Dead families, can they truly meet each other? &amp;hellip; &amp;quot; But, who could answer her! Even if they gave an answer, how much comfort could this give her!</description></item><item><title>Page 57</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-57/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-57/</guid><description>一个星期六的晚上，库兑耶尔突然带着乳酪糖球来看望彼蒂加，他恳求彼蒂加把表还给他。彼蒂加脸色一下子变白了：&amp;ldquo;我不要！请您走吧！&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;什么？叫我走？你还我表！&amp;ldquo;库兑耶尔大吵大嚷起来。 One Saturday evening, Kudeyar suddenly came to pay Petka a visit, bringing toffees and begging him to return his watch. Petka&amp;rsquo;s face instantly turned white: &amp;ldquo;No! I ask you to leave!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;What? You tell me to go? Give me back my watch!&amp;rdquo; Kudeyar started to make a big scene.</description></item><item><title>Page 57</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-57/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/zhufu/b-page-57/</guid><description>转眼又到了年底，鲁镇的人家照例都又在&amp;quot;祝福&amp;quot;。这天天色阴暗，雪花乱糟糟的飞舞着，当鲁四老爷家里迎过福神，正在大放爆竹的时候，祥林嫂倒在河边，静悄悄的死了。 In the blink of an eye, it was the end of another year, the households of Luzhen were as usual all &amp;ldquo;performing the new year&amp;rsquo;s sacrifice&amp;rdquo;. The day was gloomy, the snowflakes danced wildly in the air, just as the Lu household welcomed the God of Fortune, right when the fireworks were being set off, Xianglin&amp;rsquo;s wife collapsed by the river bank and died quietly.</description></item><item><title>Page 58</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-58/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-58/</guid><description>院长赶来了问：&amp;ldquo;怎么一回事？&amp;ldquo;彼蒂加说：&amp;ldquo;他是我的伯父，是从疯人院出来的。请您不要再放他进来了！&amp;ldquo;于是大家把库兑耶尔赶走了。 The director hurried over and asked: &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s going on here?&amp;rdquo; Petka said: &amp;ldquo;He is my uncle, he ran away from the madhouse. Please don&amp;rsquo;t let him come in again!&amp;rdquo; So everyone chased off Kudeyar.</description></item><item><title>Page 59</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-59/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-59/</guid><description>冬天到了，下起了大雪。院长叫孩子们把院子里的木材搬进库房去。彼蒂加想到心爱的表就可以到手了，所以劲头也来了：&amp;ldquo;快点儿，加油！&amp;ldquo;他干得很卖力，像个指挥官似的组织大家传递木材。 Winter came and heavy snow fell. The director called the children to carry the timber from inside the courtyard into the storehouse. Petka thought of how he could finally get his hands on his beloved watch, so he also joined with enthusiasm: &amp;ldquo;Move up, come on!&amp;rdquo; He threw himself into the task at hand and ordered everyone to pass the timber just like a commander.</description></item><item><title>Page 60</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-60/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-60/</guid><description>可是库房满了，木材没有搬完，彼蒂加大失所望，因为他的心爱的表仍然拿不出来。虽然院长表扬了他，可他感到很遗憾。 But the storage room was full before all the timber had been moved in. Petka lost all his hope, because he could not get hold of his beloved watch. Although the headmaster praised him, he felt quite sorrowful.</description></item><item><title>Page 61</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-61/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-61/</guid><description>由于他劳动积极，大家一致选举他当总务组的组长。彼蒂加又高兴起来了。 Because he had worked energetically, everyone elected him unanimously as group leader for general affairs. This cheered Petka up again.</description></item><item><title>Page 62</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-62/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-62/</guid><description>大家对他非常信任，他也热心为大家办事；他用心读书，进步很快。到新年时，他升了级，跟高年级孩子一起读书了。表的事也来不及去想了。 Everybody trusted him a lot, and he took care of all of their affairs with his full heart; he studied diligently and made good progress. When the new year started, he moved up to a higher class and studied together with the senior students. He did not have time to think about the matter of the watch anymore.</description></item><item><title>Page 63</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-63/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-63/</guid><description>日子飞快地过去了。三月里，巴黎公社纪念日这一天，孩子们去烈士陵园扫墓。他们在路上遇见了一个醉汉，大家把他推来推去，还用雪球打他的脸。彼蒂加认出那个醉汉正是库兑耶尔。 The days were passing faster and faster. In March, on the Paris Commune Memorial Day, all the kids went out to sweep the tombs at the martyrs&amp;rsquo; cemetery. On their way, they came across a drunkard. Everyone rudely pushed and pulled him back and forth and even threw snowballs at his face. Petka recognized that this drunkard was Kudeyar.</description></item><item><title>Page 64</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-64/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-64/</guid><description>库兑耶尔呻吟着、挣扎着、躲来躲去。彼蒂加忽然产生了同情心，于是跳出来，叫道：&amp;ldquo;喂，住手吧！&amp;rdquo; Kudeyar groaned, fought, and tried his best to duck away from the children. Petka suddenly felt sorry for him and so he jumped between them and shouted: &amp;ldquo;Hey, stop it!&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 65</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-65/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-65/</guid><description>库兑耶尔也认出了他，怒吼道：&amp;ldquo;你这流氓！你偷了我的表！&amp;ldquo;彼蒂加又羞又愧。 Kudeyar also recognized Petka and shouted in anger: &amp;ldquo;You rogue! You stole my watch!&amp;rdquo; Petka felt very ashamed.</description></item><item><title>Page 66</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-66/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-66/</guid><description>复活节快到了。经院长许可，彼蒂加和小伙伴米罗诺夫一起到集市上去玩耍。彼蒂加认识了一个叫娜塔莎的小女孩。他们彼此谈得很亲密，一直玩到很晚才分手。 Easter was near. The director allowed Petka to go out with his mate Milonov to spend some time at the market. There, Petka got to know a girl called Natasha. They started getting closer to each other and only separated when it was very late.</description></item><item><title>Page 67</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-67/</guid><description>积雪融化了。一天，彼蒂加发现院子里的木材也烧完了。他左思右想，一夜没睡好。第二天清早，他悄悄来到埋表的地方，把表挖了出来。表依然闪闪放光，但彼蒂加却觉得它黯然失色。 The masses of snow had melted away. One day, Petka noticed that all the timber in the yard had been used up. He pondered and pondered, and he could not sleep the entire night. The next day, he secretly went to the place where he hid the watch and dug it out. It was still sparkling and glittering, but Petka had the feeling that it had lost its splendour.</description></item><item><title>Page 68</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-68/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-68/</guid><description>这回彼蒂加该按照他的计划逃走了吧？可是，不！现在他不想离开这儿了。那表怎么办呢？扔掉它？怪愚蠢的，最好是还给库兑耶尔，但到哪儿去找他呢？彼蒂加揣着这只可恨的表，心里很痛苦。 Should Petka run away as he had planned? No, of course not! Now he did not want to leave this place. So, what should he do with the watch? Throw it away? That was quite stupid, the best option was to give it back to Kudeyar, but where could he find him? Petka hid this detestable watch in his clothes, his heart heavy.</description></item><item><title>Page 69</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-69/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-69/</guid><description>夏天到了，屋顶要油漆一下，院长叫彼蒂加上街去买油漆。他来到市场，想起先前的流浪生活，想到偷东西挨打的难堪情景&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;唉！真无聊！真糊涂！ Summer had arrived, and the roof needed to be painted. The director asked Petka to go shopping for paint. When he came to the market, he thought of his previous vagrant life and the embarrassment of stealing and being beaten up&amp;hellip; UGH! What a bore! How confusing!</description></item><item><title>Page 70</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-70/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-70/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;捉贼！捉住他！&amp;ldquo;突然传来一阵叫喊声。转眼间，从他面前跑过一个蓬头垢面的孩子。彼蒂加立刻认出那是毕塔珂夫。他一下子抓住毕塔珂夫的肩膀。毕塔珂夫一闪身，回手照他心窝就是一拳。 &amp;ldquo;Catch the thief! Catch him!&amp;rdquo; Suddenly there was shouting. In the blink of an eye, an unkempt child ran past him. Petka immediately recognized that it was Pyatakov. He grabbed Pyatakov&amp;rsquo;s shoulder at once. Pyatakov flinched, and then gave him a punch in the gut.</description></item><item><title>Page 71</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-71/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-71/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;不要撒野！你不认识我啦！我是彼蒂加。&amp;ldquo;他们来到远离街心的僻静的地方，&amp;ldquo;原谅我吧，全是我不好&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;他对毕塔珂夫讲述了那晚偷搬木材的事。 &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be wild! Don&amp;rsquo;t you know me? I&amp;rsquo;m Petka!&amp;rdquo; They came to a secluded place, away from the middle of the street, &amp;ldquo;forgive me, it's all my fault&amp;hellip;,&amp;rdquo; he told Pyatakov about the matter of stealing the wood that night.</description></item><item><title>Page 72</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-72/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-72/</guid><description>毕塔珂夫大笑起来：&amp;ldquo;可那一夜我确实弄了十六根木材，卖给小贩了&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;他敲了一下彼蒂加的前额，就踉踉跄跄地走了。 Pyatakov started laughing: &amp;ldquo;But I did get 16 pieces of lumber that night, and sold that to a black-market handler&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; he hit Petka on the forehead and staggered away.</description></item><item><title>Page 73</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-73/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-73/</guid><description>突然，毕塔珂夫又转身回来打了彼蒂加一记耳光：&amp;ldquo;把表给我！听见没有？你当我不知道？我跟库兑耶尔同住了半年监牢，他都对我讲了&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;现在他还关在监狱里。&amp;ldquo;彼蒂加真想快点儿把表交给毕塔珂夫。 Suddenly, Pyatakov turned around and slapped Petka into the face: &amp;ldquo;Give me the watch! Did you hear that? You think I don&amp;rsquo;t know? I spent half a year in jail with Kudeyar, and he told me everything&amp;hellip; he is still locked up in jail.&amp;rdquo; Petka really wanted to give the watch to Pyatakov quickly.</description></item><item><title>Page 74</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-74/</guid><description>这时，警察和一群人赶来了。毕塔珂夫被捕了。 At this time, the police and a group of people arrived. Pyatakov was arrested.</description></item><item><title>Page 75</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-75/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-75/</guid><description>彼蒂加穿过市场，闷闷不乐地向颜料店走去。他狠狠地捏住口袋里的表：我要这包袱干什么？这个倒霉的玩艺儿！他转过街角，忽然看见一个卖表链的小女孩，原来是娜塔莎。 Petka crossed the market and walked to the paint shop gloomily. He squeezed the watch in his pocket fiercely: What do I want this burden for? This hapless game! As he turned around the corner of the street, he suddenly saw a girl selling a watch chain. The girl turned out to be Natasha.</description></item><item><title>Page 76</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-76/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-76/</guid><description>他分明认得，那表链正是库兑耶尔的。他问娜塔莎表链是从哪儿来的。她说：&amp;ldquo;这是我爸爸的。他从监狱捎来一封信，叫我卖&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;我没办法生活&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; He clearly recognized that the watch chain belonged to Kudeyar. He asked Natasha where the watch chain came from. She said: &amp;ldquo;This is my father's. He sent a letter from prison asking me to sell it… I can&amp;rsquo;t live like this…&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Page 77</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-77/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-77/</guid><description>彼蒂加觉得脑袋在胀大，脚下的地面在摇动，他几乎要跌倒了。他把表链接过来，久久地端详着&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; Petka felt his head swell and the ground under his feet shaking, and he almost fell. He took the watch chain and looked at it for a long time…</description></item><item><title>Page 78</title><link>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-78/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://readchina.github.io/comics/biao/b-page-78/</guid><description>他从衣袋里掏出那只表，用发抖的手把它挂在表链上，递给娜塔莎说：&amp;ldquo;给你！&amp;ldquo;然后，飞快地跑走，消失在喧闹的人群中了。 He took the watch out of his pocket, attached it to the watch chain with trembling hands and handed it to Natasha: &amp;ldquo;Here, for you!&amp;rdquo; Then he ran away quickly and disappeared into the noisy crowd.</description></item></channel></rss>